<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>copywriting &#8211; Milena Majczak</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>SAAS Marketing Done the Right Way</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 09:59:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Tips on the text construction</title>
		<link>./../../../2020/08/11/tips-on-the-text-construction/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=tips-on-the-text-construction</link>
					<comments>./../../../2020/08/11/tips-on-the-text-construction/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 09:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[copywriting]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=633</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>You have already tried to write your perfect copy but your content doesn’t drive traffic.&#160;How to structure your text to catch readers attention? Here are a few writing tips on the text structure used by writing professionals – journalists.&#160; I. Title Should be catchy. It must attract the reader’s attention. &#160;You can use for that &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="./../../../2020/08/11/tips-on-the-text-construction/index.html"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Tips on the text construction</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2020/08/11/tips-on-the-text-construction/index.html">Tips on the text construction</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Milena Majczak</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>You have already tried to write your perfect copy but your content doesn’t drive traffic.&nbsp;How to structure your text to catch readers attention? Here are a few writing tips on the text structure used by writing professionals – journalists.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<h3>I. Title</h3>



<p>Should be catchy. It must attract the reader’s attention. &nbsp;You can use for that an alliteration or a wordplay. Title needs to be concise, short and contain the message, the main point that we want to get across.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>II. Lead</h3>



<p>Most of the news articles contain lead which follows the title. Lead is a kind of a summary which gives the overall idea of the text. Similarly to title it needs to catch the reader’s attention. It must be short, precise and informative. Blog texts rarely contain lead, and writing it is not necessary. Personally, I prefer texts with leads, because only then I get an idea whether the text is worth reading or not.</p>



<h3>III. The main body</h3>



<h4><strong>1. Beginning, Kick-in</strong></h4>



<p>Sometimes good stories need a good start and here is where the so called “kick in” comes into play. It is usually an introductory paragraph, a picture which provides the background to your story. It might be a situation, a person an interesting event. This point is not a must but it raises the reader’s interest and is the the perfect beginning. The kick-in can start from a generalization, anecdote, metaphor, rhetorical question, a story, situation, joke or sarcasm.</p>



<h4><strong>2.  Billboard</strong></h4>



<p>In billboard we are informing the reader why the text needs to be read, what is that interesting thing that we want to say. Here one can refer to the future as well as the most recent facts. An essential part of billboard might be a piece of new information or (news).</p>



<h5>&nbsp;<strong>b) Thesis statement/ hypothesis</strong></h5>



<p>Thesis statement is your opinion on the given topic. Usually it is stated at the end of the billboard. However, one can put it in the “kick-in” . Good thesis describes the situation, process, problem which we observe and shouldn’t be longer than one or two sentences.</p>



<h4><strong>3. Arguments&nbsp;</strong></h4>



<p>Arguments are the facts which are essential for supporting the thesis and need to be proven by evidence. Here one can put quotes, statistics, data that strictly refer to a thesis.</p>



<h3><strong>IV. Summation or the Kick out</strong></h3>



<p>Kick-out is the end of the article. A good kick-out leaves the reader with some doubt and makes him reflect on the article.&nbsp;</p>



<p>—————————————————————————————————————————————————————–</p>



<p>You are probably now asking yourself “Why do I actually need all this? I am not a journalist and I will never be”.</p>



<p>It is true that writing a news article is not exactly the same as writing a blog post. The latter is more informal in style and doesn’t seem to follow any strict rules.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I have noticed that many bloggers, companies give their opinions without supporting their view with arguments. Why should your reader’s trust you? Is it just because you are an influencer in your niche with thousands of followers and satisfied clients? Or do you want to show that you create even more value providing evidence for your opinions?</p>



<p>Even the best content will get lost in the sea of information if it is not structured properly.&nbsp;Sometimes bloggers have a lot of interesting things to say but don’t know how to get their point across. Good writing is always at the value and is a craft that&nbsp;can be learnt by anyone. What do you think? Can the rules of news writing be useful for bloggers and content marketers?&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2020/08/11/tips-on-the-text-construction/index.html">Tips on the text construction</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Milena Majczak</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2020/08/11/tips-on-the-text-construction/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
